<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Arc - Devs ♥ Security</title><description>Code, Security, and Everything in Between.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 18:43:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/tag/arc/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Hacking (old) Hacker News: fun with weak passwords and Arc</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When I was conducting my cloud password security research I also looked at &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;. It's not a cloud application, but it does have pretty common password security qualities. It's also interesting because it's written in Arc (a Lisp dialect) and the code is available (the old version from 2009).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
When you create a Hacker News account you can create passwords 4 characters long without any restrictions on the password complexity. This mean that you can have a password that looks like 0000 or 1111. Sure, not everybody will use passwords like that, but there's a good chance that quite a few users will have pretty simple passwords. Even technical people are still people and people choose the easiest possible passwords (when they can) making it easy to conduct online password attacks.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
What's interesting is that when you change your password you are required to have, at least, 8 characters (still without any complexity requirements). The Arc source code shows that it used to be 4 characters as well. Time to look at the code to see what else might be there...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the login code from app.arc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(def good-login (user pw ip)
  (let record (list (seconds) ip user)
    (if (and user pw (aand (shash pw) (is it (hpasswords* user))))
        (do (unless (user-&amp;gt;cookie* user) (cook-user user))
            (enq-limit record good-logins*)
            user)
        (do (enq-limit record bad-logins*)
            nil))))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting part is &lt;code&gt;(aand (shash pw) (is it (hpasswords* user)))&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;br&gt;
the password parameter is hashed and then compared to the expected hash for the user. &lt;br&gt;
What makes it interesting is the &lt;code&gt;is&lt;/code&gt; operator that determines if two values in Arc are equal. &lt;br&gt;
Let's find out what &lt;code&gt;is&lt;/code&gt; really means...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;is&lt;/code&gt; is defined in ac.scm as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(xdef is (lambda args (pairwise ar-is2 args)))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ar-is2&lt;/code&gt; is the function that implements the interesting parts we care about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(define (ar-is2 a b)
  (tnil (or (eqv? a b)
            (and (string? a) (string? b) (string=? a b))
            (and (ar-false? a) (ar-false? b)))))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important part here is this bit of Scheme code &lt;code&gt;(string=? a b)&lt;/code&gt; that checks if two strings are equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's how MzScheme defines its string compare operator "string=?":&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GEN_STRING_COMP(string_eq, "string=?", mz_char_strcmp, ==, 0, 1)
...
static int mz_char_strcmp(const char *who, const mzchar *str1, int l1, const mzchar *str2, int l2, 
        int use_locale, int size_shortcut)
{
  int endres;

  if (size_shortcut &amp;amp;&amp;amp; (l1 != l2))
    return 1;
  //... (cut unused locale compare)
  if (l1 &amp;gt; l2) {
    l1 = l2;
    endres = 1;
  } else {
    if (l2 &amp;gt; l1)
      endres = -1;
    else
      endres = 0;
  }

  while (l1--) {
    unsigned int a, b;

    a = *(str1++);
    b = *(str2++);

    a = a - b;
    if (a)
      return a;
  }

  return endres;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a standard string compare implementation that returns as soon as the current characters don't match. &lt;br&gt;
This means that the password checking code is vulnerable to timing attacks (in theory). It's harder to exploit because the code doesn't compare raw/cleartext passwords. Instead, the code compares password hashes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are those hashes? The answer is in the &lt;code&gt;shash&lt;/code&gt; function in app.arc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(def shash (str)
  (let fname (+ "/tmp/shash" (rand-string 10))
    (w/outfile f fname (disp str f))
    (let res (tostring (system (+ "openssl dgst -sha1 &amp;lt;" fname)))
      (do1 (cut res 0 (- (len res) 1))
           (rmfile fname)))))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;shash&lt;/code&gt; creates a SHA1 hash (without a "salt") and that hash is used to verify the user identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The publicly available code is from 2009 and the current password management and processing code has been improved since then. It sounds like the current unreleased version might be using a pure Scheme implementation of bcrypt. &lt;br&gt;
It would be nice to see it given that there aren't a lot of pure Scheme bcrypt implementations out there :-) In the meantime you can explore an inner hacker inside you and deploy the old code yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To run Arc 3.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href="http://download.plt-scheme.org/v372.html"&gt;MzScheme v372&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href="http://ycombinator.com/arc/arc3.tar"&gt;Arc3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the instructions in "how-to-run-news" :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To run Arc 3.1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Racket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href="http://ycombinator.com/arc/arc3.1.tar"&gt;Arc3.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; is not alone when it comes to no password complexity requirements. 
Quite a few companies have the same password qualities (see &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/the-sad-state-of-password-security-in-the-cloud"&gt;"The Sad State of Password Security in the Cloud"&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about it). Unlike Hacker News, where you don't gain much by compromising users (unless they reuse the password in other more valuable internet sites or cloud apps), other companies do have valuable information that should be protected a little better.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/hacking-old-hacker-news-fun-with-weak-passwords-and-arc/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">934c53b9-9db9-423a-98ac-5935e2d1fda8</guid><category>passwords</category><category>security</category><category>Arc</category><category>Lisp</category><dc:creator>Kyle Quest</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 17:34:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>